Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
You're going to ruin her if you continue to
do nothing more than let her live with you.
（レンフレッド）
このまま
お前と暮らすだけにさせていたら
彼女はダメになるぞ
Elias...
（チセ）エリアス…
That's right.
（リンデル）そう
His name was given to him by my master.
あやつの名前は
わしの師匠が
授けたものなのよ
Welcome, Elias, to this
dizzying, disgusting, beautiful world.
（ラハブ）
エリアス ようこそ
目まぐるしく 醜くも美しい世界へ
All right, take care of Elias for me,
それじゃあ エリアスを頼んだよ
Lindel.
リンデル
This is all so sudden.
（リンデル）唐突だのう
Well, from now on, you're Elias.
では 今から おぬしはエリアスだ
For a few years, the two of us
traveled the forest, chasing reindeer.
（リンデル）
それから数年余り
わしらは共に
トナカイを追いながら森を歩き
We traveled, enjoying the sight
of the lakes and fields as we went.
湖を眺め
野を見て 旅した
（ウサギ）キイーッ
おい 何をしとる
Hey, what are you doing?
You shouldn't take things you aren't even going to eat.
食うでもないのに捕るのは
やめい！
（エリアス）そうなの？
I shouldn't?
フウ…
Elias seemed to be missing something.
（リンデル）
エリアスは
何かが欠けておるようだった
He learned quickly, but he seemed as though
he was looking at everything from the outside.
覚えは早いが 全てを
外側から眺めているふうに見えた
One day, when we were running
low on food, we visited a home.
そんな折
食料が少なくなり 人里へ寄った
Hello, I'm a shaman.
（リンデル）
もし　わしは まじない師だ
Is there anyone sick or injured here?
病や傷を患う者はおるか？
Would you spare me some food in exchange for healing?
治す代わりに 少し食料を
恵んでもらいたいのだが…
My grandson happens to be bedridden.
（村長）
ちょうど
孫が寝込んでおりまして…
I can make use of my hands for a fever.
（リンデル）
熱ならば
この手も少しは役に立とう
（少年）ハア… ハア…
It must be awful for you.
（リンデル）
つらかろう　じきに良くなる
You'll be better soon.
Sleep well.
しっかり眠りや
You're his little sister?
（リンデル）妹か？
Don't worry.
心配するな
Your brother will be fine.
兄は じきに…
（少女）その人…
That man...
影の中に何かいる
There's something in his shadow.
怖い！
I'm scared!
（リンデル）あっ…
（村長）おい！ どうした？
What is it?!
It's a monster!
（老婆）化け物よ！
A m-monster!
ばっ 化け物…
早く！
Hurry!
（村長）魔物だ！
（村人）悪魔だ！
It's evil!
It's a demon!
He was going to take the kid!
（村人）
子供を
連れていくつもりだったんだ！
There was a child with the sight in the house.
聡(さと)い子供がおったか… クソ！
Shit.
Sorry, Lindel.
（エリアス）リンデル ごめん
It's not your fault.
おぬしのせいではない！
You demon!
（村人たち）
悪魔め！
出ていけ！
（リンデル）うっ…
（村人）悪魔だ！
Demon!
I'll kill you!
（村人）ぶち殺してやる！
Evil!
魔物だ！
悪魔め！
Demon!
悪魔！
ぶち殺してやる！
I'll kill you!
ひ… 人を呼べ！
Send for help!
Stop, Elias!
やめろ エリアス！
Veil of the forest, lift yourself for us!
森のベールよ
その裾を我らに開(ひら)け！
He's gone.
（村人）消えた…
Where are we?
（エリアス）ここは…
This is where the forest gods live.
森の神たちが棲(す)む側じゃ
Lindel.
（エリアス）リンデル？
（リンデル）ハア… ハア…
This is what happens when I force myself to use magic.
無理やり 魔法を使うと こうなる
We need to get out of here.
早く出なければ
Spruce.
（リンデル）
トウヒ…
（エリアス）連れていって
Take us outside, to Lindel's reindeer.
外のリンデルのトナカイのそばへ
I taught him that.
（リンデル）
わしが教えた…
You're surprisingly good with your hands.
おぬし 意外と器用なんだの
I've seen you do this lots of times.
（エリアス）
何回も
君がやってるのを見てるもの
Thanks.
ありがとう
どうかしたか？
Is something wrong?
Lindel,
（エリアス）リンデル…
（リンデル）ん？
I'm pretty sure I've eaten humans before.
（エリアス）僕は きっと…
人間を食べたことがあるんだと思う
What do you think, Chise?
（リンデル）チセは どう思う？
What if he's a man-eating monster?
あやつが人食いの化け物であったら
I could see things from the
other side ever since I was little.
（チセ）
私は 小さいころから ずっと
あちら側のものが見えて
A lot of them would talk about
how tasty or gross humans are.
人間を おいしいとか まずいとか
言うものも たくさんいて
I was really scared.
本当に怖くて…
But Elias has never scared me, not once.
でも エリアスは…
怖いなんて
一度も思ったことないんです
だから
あのヒトが昔 本当に…
So, if he really used to...
それ以上は あれに直接言ってやれ
Tell him the rest yourself.
But you were the one who asked.
リンデルさんが聞いたのに…
My bad.
いや すまん すまん
You're well-spoken.
おぬしは きちんと話せる
You should talk to him lots, too.
あれにも同じように
いろいろ話してやってくれ
What did you say in response, Lindel?
（チセ）
リンデルさんは
何て返したんですか？
Me?
（リンデル）わしか？ わしは…
I said...
I bet I'm tasty. Don't eat me.
わしは うまいだろうが
食ってくれるなよ
I'm... not going to eat you.
（エリアス）た… 食べないよ？
Okay, good.
なら よい
But sometimes I feel the urge to...
（エリアス）
でも 僕は時々 食べたくなる
嫌なはずなのに…
Even though I'm sure I don't really want to.
Aren't humans afraid of things like me?
人間は僕のようなヤツを
怖がるんじゃないの？
Hey, there are lots of things that eat humans.
なに この世に人を食うものなど
ごまんといるわ
わしが お前だけを
殊更 恐れるいわれはない
I have no reason to be fearful of you in particular.
Eat all kinds of things, and soon enough,
（リンデル）
もっと たくさんのものを食え
そうすれば
you'll forget all about your ambivalent taste for humans.
気乗りしない人の味など
すぐ忘れるさ
と… まあ
半ば無理やり 話を流した
I kind of killed the conversation on purpose.
I was actually scared, after all.
実際 怖かったしの
You were, huh?
怖かったんですか？
You'd be shocked, too, at least for a moment,
膝の上で丸まる猫が
実は人食いと知れたら
if you found out that the cat curled up on
your lap actually ate humans, wouldn't you?
一瞬でも驚くじゃろ？
（リンデル）シャーッ
（チセ）例えが猫…
Comparing him to a cat?
（ルツ）ハア…
Either way, my fears vanished
as soon as I took a sip of the soup.
だが 恐れなど
スープをひとさじ すくって含めば
消えたさ
Also, that soup tasted unbelievably bad.
ちなみに そのときのスープは
どえらく まずかった
（リンデル）げえ〜！
Thank goodness for Silky.
（チセ）
シルキーがいて よかった
Still, humans are the most
easily-scared and cruel creatures of all.
とはいえ…
人間は どんな生き物より
臆病で残酷だからの
なるべく そのことは
言わないほうがいいだろうと
I told him he shouldn't tell people about it too much.
ヤツに言い含めた
しかし
あのときの助言が効いているのか
I don't know if he's following my
advice, or if something else happened...
ほかに何かあったのか
But he absolutely refuses to tell people about himself.
あれは徹底して
自分のことを他人に漏らさん
He's still stuck as a child.
あれは まだ 子供のままなのだ
Sorry for the long talk.
長話をして すまんの
You should get some sleep.
そろそろ お眠り
Can't sleep, Chise?
（ルツ）チセ… 眠れないのか？
Nah, thanks, Ruth.
ありがとう ルツ
Did I look tasty?
（チセ）
私… おいしそうに見えたのかな
I guess I've heard something he didn't want to say.
あのヒトが言いたくないことを
聞いちゃったんなら…
朝だぞ
It's morning.
Oh, right, I'm in the land of dragons.
そっか ドラゴンの国…
（チセ）おはようございます
Good morning.
Morning.
（リンデル）おはよう
Chise!
（雛竜(ひなりゅう)たち）
チセだ！
人間だ！
Human!
おはよ〜！ おはよ〜！
Morning!
Morning.
（チセ）おはよう…
Morning—
（ルツ）チセ〜！
Chise!
That girl sure does fall into water a lot.
（リンデル）
あれは とことん水に落ちるの
ぷはっ！
Chise, are you all right?
（ルツ）チセ！ 大丈夫か？
There was this amazing thing.
（チセ）すごいの… いた
Why are you cutting my hair?
（チセ）
髪を切って どうするんですか？
Even since long ago, hair has always carried magic.
（リンデル）
古(いにしえ)より 髪には魔力が宿るものでな
We'll use this as the core of the wand.
これを杖(つえ)の芯にする
You don't see many Asians with red hair like yours.
チセは東洋の者には珍しい赤毛だな
It's a perfect color for magic.
魔法には ぴったりの色じゃ
Red is the color of the earth,
赤は大地の色
星に流れる炎と血の色なのだ
the color of the flames and
blood flowing through the stars.
Choose a handpiece from one of these.
握りは ここから選びや
The red elderberry knocks on
the door to the black goddess.
ニワトコは
黒い女神への戸をたたく木
The willow lingers between the living and the dead.
ヤナギは生ける者と死せる者の
あわいに たたずむ
ハシバミは あらゆる厄を退ける木
The hazel wards off evil.
The yew is a symbol of eternity.
イチイは永遠のしるし
It can draw or banish magic.
魔法に親しく また 祓(はら)う
The checker tree has a powerful life
force and brings order to the wicked.
ナナカマドは強い命を持ち
妖(あや)しのものを従わせる
I saw him when I first came here.
（チセ）
初めて来たとき 見た子だ
ふわあ〜
I had him dry the wood out.
生木から水分を抜いてもらったのさ
Well, let's get to carving.
では 削りに入るとするか
Oh, sorry, there's nothing for me to teach you.
（リンデル）ああ すまんな
教えることはないのだ
Just carve it as you like,
so that it's comfortable for you to use.
（リンデル）
使いやすいように
好きな形に削るといい
It's customary for one to carve their
own wands, and for their senior to finish it.
杖は己で作り
仕上げを年長者がするのが
習わしでな
It would be good to talk to yourself as you're carving.
削っている間に
己と話すのもいいだろう
To myself?
自分と？
I'll go take a look around.
（リンデル）
わしは見回りをしてくるから
おぬしは ゆっくりやれ
Take your time.
（チセ）ハア…
Talk to myself?
（チセ）
自分と話す…
あくまで 自分と話すんだろ
You have to talk to yourself, don't you?
ルツ〜
Ruth...
I guess I've never really thought about myself until now.
（チセ）
私…
自分のこと
何にも考えてこなかったんだ
It's dark now.
もう暗いぞ　休め
Take a break.
That's some amazing focus.
すごい集中力だの
You're almost done.
ほぼ終わりではないか
（チセ）え… はい
Right.
Just a little more work.
あと少し… ですね
ほう
初めての仕事にしては上出来だの
Not bad at all, for a beginner.
Let's finish it tomorrow.
明日は仕上げだ
The moon's bright tonight.
（リンデル）今夜は月が明るい
I can show you something nice.
いいものが見せられるぞ
The moss here grows flowers.
ここの苔(こけ)には花が咲く
Flowers?
（チセ）花？
The elves created this land.
（リンデル）
この大地はエルフが生み 愛する地
They adore it.
エルフと踊れば 花も咲く
Dance with the elves, and the flowers will bloom.
わしの別の名を知っておるか？
Do you know my other name?
（チセ）
百花(ひゃっか)の歌…“エコーズ”ですか？
Echos, the song of a hundred flowers?
Names are very important for mages and sorcerers.
（リンデル）
魔法使いや魔術師にとって
名前は とても大事なものでな
Usually, they're called by the name that
describes their features and their true nature.
常ならば
本質や特徴を表す名で呼ばれる
My spells are songs.
わしの呪文は歌なのだ
Let's have them bloom for us, just for tonight.
今夜は特別に咲いてもらおう
Iruna Etelero
Nadia, Ezelevoteh
Lezelkoh, Mikemesta
Iruna Etelero
Satoa, Aimeltewa
（チセ）
それは雪解けの水の音に似て
Like snowmelt, it was both low and high.
Lezelkoh, Mikemesta
低く 高く 朗々と風に乗って
It resonated through the wind.
Ahmeruh, Mikelmoh
Let's dance.
（エルフＡ）踊ろう
（エルフＢ）踊ろう！
Toimessez, Mikelmoh
Let's dance.
（チセ）えっ… エルフ？
Elves?
I've never danced before.
私 踊ったことなんて…
Just twirl around with them.
（セルキー）
一緒に
クルクルしてればいいのですよ
Masseri, Imekuwozeh
Listen carefully to the sound, to the song,
（リンデル）音に耳を澄ませ
歌に 風の音に 水の音に
to the sound of the wind, to the sound of the water.
Towonnah, Mizaimesta
Humanity still remembers the sounds
人は覚えておる
Kessellah, Kessellah
はるか太古 言葉よりも先に生まれ
体に満ちた音を
that filled our bodies from long
ago, before even language itself.
Kessellah, Sehtoru
Ahmelva, Etelerovoh
（リンデル）魔法も同じよ
Magic is the same way.
Listen to what is around you, and offer out your hand.
己の周りに耳を貸し 手を伸ばせ
Mitetevah, Mariah, Ezelevotech,
You still remember that.
お前は それを覚えている
Lezelkoh, Mikemesta
（チセ）も… もうダメ
I'm spent.
ハア… ハア…
I wonder what he would say, if he saw this scene.
（チセ）
あのヒトが
この景色を見たら
どう言うのかな
Elias.
エリアス！
（エリアス）え？ チセ？
Chise.
どうして水鏡なんか？
Why did you make a water mirror?
A water mirror?
水鏡…
A water mirror lets you see a person through the water.
（エリアス）
水を通じて相手の姿を見るのが
水鏡さ
Huh?
あれ…
Is he singing right now?
あいつ 今 歌ってる？
Yes.
（チセ）はい
（エリアス）どうりでね
No wonder.
His magic connected there to here.
あいつの魔力で
こっちとあっちが つながったんだ
I see.
（チセ）そうですか…
エリアス
Elias...
Yeah?
You look troubled.
（チセ）
何だか 難しい顔をしていますけど
何か あったんですか？
Did something happen?
I suppose.
（エリアス）そうだね… 少し
A little.
えっ… 大丈夫ですか？
Is everything okay?
（エリアス）
君がいないと…
Home is a bit cold without you.
何だか 家が寒いよ
Even though it's summer, and I have the stove on.
今は夏で
暖炉も焚(た)いてるのにね
The flowers are beautiful here.
（チセ）こっちは花が きれいです
あなたにも見せられたらいいのに
I wish I could show you.
Take them in, and tell me about them when you get back.
（エリアス）
君が見て
帰ってきたら 僕に教えてよ
Here's a small taste.
（チセ）お裾分けです
（チセ）エリアス？
Elias,
I heard all kinds of things about you.
私 あなたのことを
いろいろ聞いてしまったんです
That old bastard...
（エリアス）あのジジイ…
So I'll tell you what I haven't been able to tell you, too.
だから 私も
あなたに
言えなかったこと
話します
I'll head home as soon as my wand's done.
杖が出来たら すぐ帰りますね
Okay.
（エリアス）うん お願い
Please.
Two kids.
（リンデル）
子供が２人
I don't even have kids, but I
feel like I'm raising both of them.
子供もいないのに
子育てしてる気分だの
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
（チセ）
帰る場所を持たなかった少女
A girl who hadn't a place to return is
shown the way by Lindenbaum's staff.
リンデンバウムの杖が
彼女の行く末を示す
What does she choose at the end of her wandering?
彷徨(ほうこう)の果てに少女が選んだのは…
Please... Connect me to that person.
（チセ）
お願い　あのヒトの所へ つないで